Alain Galvan

Undergraduate Research Assistant at Florida International University

me@alaingalvan.com

Summary

Hi, I'm a Graphics Research Assistant for FIU, focused on Shaders, GPGPU Computing, Game Development, and making tools for artists.

I love making Digital Art like Digital Paintings, 3D Models, Pixel Art. I'm a pianist/guitarist for Princeton Church in Homestead, as well as a speaker for FIU and the Miami Game Developer Meetups.

Feel free to message me!

Honors and Awards

1st Place SudoHacks 2016

Stetson University

April 2016

We won 1st place for making an RESTful api abstraction layer on top of PeopleSoft with the addition of analytics and a modern frontend.

3rd Place UHack 2016

University of Miami

February 2016

Won 3rd place for a web application that trains beginners to read music by plugging in their piano and playing in real time.

Codepen.io Frontpage

Codepen.io

March 2016

I've been front paged multiple times for the following:

- 1. A 3D connected Stellar Cloud done with Three.js
- 2. A 3D Baked Codepen Logo
- 3. A ReactJS Hero Component
- 4. A Soundcloud Angular Component
- 5. A 3D CSS Book Element

Newgrounds Frontpage

Newgrounds.com

May 2014

Awarded for a concept screenshot of a pixel art RPG. Received over 16K views.

Intel Excelence in Computer Science

February 2011

Awarded for showcasing kinematics and physical programming techniques.

Experience

Undergraduate Graphics Research Assistant at Florida International University

June 2015 - Present (1 year 2 months)

I'm responsible for creating an Unreal Engine 4 research project adding a procedurally generated skybox system and Windows 8 multitouch support. This project was further developed into a gesture elicitation experiment system, as well as a paper published to a conference.

In addition, I serve as a Teacher's Assistant for Web Application Development creating assignments/exams/grading, and give workshops on Khronos Standards (OpenGL, OpenCL, WebGL, WebCL), Unreal Engine 4, HTML5 and Node.js.

Game Developer at Florida International University

December 2014 - June 2015 (7 months)

Modeling, animation, rigging, vector art, web development, server development, music composition, C# programming, Unity Development.

Full Stack Developer (Node.js) at AeroLocate

December 2013 - January 2015 (1 year 2 months)

Web application development using the latest standards and technologies. (Node.js, MongoDB, AngularJS, WebGL)

Education

Florida International University

Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer Science, 2012 - 2016 Activities and Societies: OpenHID Research Assistant

Ronald W. Reagan/Doral High School

2008 - 2012

Activities and Societies: Physics Club, Choir

Volunteer Experience

Worship Leader at The Way Church of Miami

July 2010 - November 2013

I served as a worship leader, performing every service on Piano, Guitar, or Violin. In addition, I educated new worshipers, and served as a technical director for the church's computer systems.

Worship Leader at Princeton Christian Church

September 2014 - Present

I serve as a worshiper playing electric and acoustic guitar, in addition to serving as the backup pianist or bassist.

Speaker at Miami Game Developer Meetup

September 2015 - Present

I've taught in numerous meetups with topics related to game development, including:

- Zbrush Modeling
- Pixel Art Design
- Game Maker Studio Programming
- Making Art for Games

Projects

Ora

October 2012 to Present

Members: Alain Galvan

An indie Steam Game that was featured in the YoYo Games October 2012 Steam Workshop Competition. Received More than 2000 views and 1000 subscriptions.

Guardian

August 2010 to Present

Members: Alain Galvan

An indie RPG that was a finalist for the YoYo Games August 2010 Competition 6.

Languages

English

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

Spanish

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

Skills & Expertise

GLSL

OpenGL

OpenGL ES

WebGL

Unity3D

Zbrush

C#

TypeScript

JavaScript

Digital Painting

SASS

Three.js

AngularJS

3D Studio Max

Blender

Game Maker Studio

Mudbox

Vector Illustration

3D Modeling

Pixel Art

HTML 5

Node.js

Game Development

Web Development

Programming

Software Design

Java

HTML5

C++

 \mathbf{C}

HTML

Linux

MySQL

Photoshop

Python

CSS

Interests

Game Development, Digital Painting, 3D Modeling, Composing Music, Performing Music, Guitar, Violin, Piano, Cooking

Courses

Undergraduate Graphics Research Assistant

Florida International University

Principles of Computer Graphics

Computational Geometry

Alain Galvan

Undergraduate Research Assistant at Florida International University

me@alaingalvan.com



Contact Alain on LinkedIn